Alex Wendland

PHONE: +44 7854033626 GitHub: https://github.com/AlexWendland E-MAIL: alex@wendland.org.uk

WEBSITE: https://alex-wendland.notion.site/Alex-Wendland-1c54946631524bc88doa8f2c9fa16f08

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an ethical data specialist with a passion for automation, mathematics and most importantly solving problems. I apply the scientific method (conjecture-test-learn-repeat) in all layers of my life. I have led projects, teams and organisations with a focus on sustainable learning, efficiency and communication.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2021-2023

Data Scientist - CRYPTOCOMPARE, LONDON

- · Researched and developed a data pipeline to process, store and analyse blockchain data.
- Developed a CI/CD pipeline for our data monitoring microservices using docker, github actions, Azure cloud storage and kubernetes.
- Sought out and built relationships with established data analytics and visualisation providers to build a long-term mutually-beneficial partnership.
- Worked with clients to research, formalise, and implement metrics on over 100TB of data and the sales team to deliver multiple repeat customers.
- Set up and ran monthly educational seminars on blockchain data with a wide audience.
- Created and led the product development team to deliver multiple new products to market.
- Formed a cross-team data organisation to improve collaboration, coding standards, and knowledge of our tech stack.

2020-2021

Civil Service, Science and Engineering Fast Stream - CABINET OFFICE, LONDON

- Project-managed high-profile technical reports with multiple stakeholders within the Advisory Council for the Misuse of Drugs: ACMD advice on consumer cannabidiol (CBD) products and Consideration of barriers to research: part 1.
- Managed internal stakeholders by developing road maps, regular updates, and resolving different requirements, and external stakeholders by organising call for evidence sessions, evidence gathering sessions, and public correspondence.
- Organised the analysis of the departmental staff survey to derive key targets with the objective to increase inclusivity and diversity.

2015-2020

Reseacher - University of Warwick - Department of Mathematics

- Won multiple awards whilst building a strong academic portfolio in leading journals such as Advances in Mathematics, Annals of Applied Probability and the Journal of Graph Theory.
- Worked with Centre for Science and Policy, Heathrow airport and Defence Science and Technology Laboratory.
- Was an award winning teacher at all levels and formats: lecturing masters level courses to helping underprivileged A-Level students one-on-one.
- Earned funding in 2013 from JISC to develop a virtual learning platform in django (python).
- Chaired the main student forum for change within the department for 3 years and was an active member of our diversity committee.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2020 PhD in Mathematics, University of Warwick, Coventry

"Generalisations of Groups and Cayley Graphs" under the supervision of Agelos Georgakopoulos

2011 – 2015 Masters in Mathematics, University of Warwick, Coventry

1st Class Hons (91% average)

2004 - 2011 Secondary school, Beechen Cliff School, Bath

A Levels: Further Maths (A^*) , Maths (A^*) , Physics (A)

KEY SKILLS

Developer-level languages: Pyth

Python and LATEX

Working-level languages:

C, SQL, Shell and JavaScript

Tools: Transferable: Git, Github actions, Google suite, Docker, Kubernetes, Obsidian, notion and Web3. Problem solving (Devloped mutliple products focusing on customer pain points), Project Management (Led multiple across-team projects), and Communication

(lecturing to large audiences, built relationships with clients and partners)